## NISHANTH KUMAR

+91-9902637227



nishanthk.35@gmail.com



Mumbai



### Data Analyst

### **SUMMARY**

Data Analyst with 2+ years of experience in data analysis, with an overall professional experience of 5+ years. I possess a solid foundation in Machine Learning, Python and SQL, bolstered by a rigorous Post Graduate Program in Data Science and Business Analytics. My specialization in quantitative analysis allows me to provide comprehensive, data-driven insights

### **EDUCATION**

### **McCombs School of Business**

Data Science and Business Analytics (PGP) 2021 – 2022

### Sahyadri College of Engineering

Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical) 2012 – 2016

### SKILLS

- Python
- Machine Learning
- Databricks
- SQL
- Advanced Excel
- Tableau/Power BI

# EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

 Participated in CSR initiative at CRISIL, where I volunteered to teach English to students in rural areas, helping to enhance their language skills and educational opportunities.

### LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi
- Kannada

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Data Analyst at CRISIL

Oct 2022- Present

- Utilize Databricks, SQL, and Python for data analysis, visualization, and reporting, ensuring accurate and timely delivery of insights.
- Developed and automated custom web scraping scripts using Python (Selenium) to extract and organize large datasets from diverse websites.
- Automated Excel validations using Python scripts, significantly reducing manual labour and minimizing human error across multiple files.
- Built dashboards using PowerBI for internal team to provide up to date data and valuable insights using visualization. Well versed with Tableau as well.
- Also worked on building and testing quantitative estimation models for the "Corporate Wallets" offering, enabling benchmarking and market share analysis for global investment banks
- Working on **ad-hoc analysis** and supporting central research team on multiple research requests using Advanced excel and Power query.

#### Quantative Analyst Intern (CRISIL)

- Built LSTM model on Bitcoin stock price data (Time Series) with a model accuracy of 86.53 %. Performed Data cleaning and performed EDA to identify trends, patterns and hidden insights.
- Built BERT model (NLP) on Bitcoin tweets data to analyze the sentiment of the tweets regarding Bitcoin. The model inferred that most sentiment of the tweets were positive.
- Finally we performed combined analysis of Bitcoin stock price and Bitcoin tweets to see if the Bitcoin tweets have any effect on the Bitcoin trade volume. Using Spearman correlation we had enough evidence to conclude that there is a correlation between the Bitcoin traded volume and the number of tweets.

### PREVIOUS EXPERIENCE

**Technical Support Analyst at XSEED** Jan 2022 - Oct 2022

**Technical Support at IBM** Feb 2019 - Aug 2021

Amin Electrical Works Jan 2017 - Sep 2018